beaming internet from the middle of the woods
从树林中间发射互联网
using an extra large pizza sized satellite dish
使用超大比萨饼大小的卫星天线
placed on top of your house
放在你的房子上面
up to a satellite orbiting
直到卫星轨道
550 kilometers outside Earth's atmosphere
离地球大气层550公里
well let's be honest is technologically mind blowing
好吧，老实说，技术上令人兴奋。
what's even crazier
更疯狂的是
is that the Starlink satellites move incredibly fast
星链卫星移动得非常快
around 27 thousand kilometers per hour
时速大约2.70万公里
and data is being sent back and forth between them
数据在他们之间来回发送
at hundreds of megabits per second
每秒数百兆比特
all while the dish and satellite
同时天线和卫星
are continuously angling
正在不断地倾斜
or steering the beam of data
或者操纵数据束
pointed directly between them
直接指向他们之间
on top of that
除此之外
the dish switches between different satellites
天线在不同的卫星之间切换
every four or so minutes
每四分钟左右
because they move out of the dish's field of view
因为它们移出了盘子的视野
rather quickly
相当快
if you have no clue as to how this is possible
如果你不知道这怎么可能
stick around
逗留
because we're going to dive into the multiple
因为我们将深入研究倍数
key technologies
关键技术
which enable satellite internet
启用卫星互联网
to magically work
神奇地工作
first we'll explore inside the satellite dish
首先我们将探索卫星天线内部
and see how it generates a beam of data that is
看看它是如何生成一束数据的
able to reach space
能够到达太空
second
第二
we'll see how this dish continuously steers the beam
我们将看到这个盘子如何持续地控制光束
so that it points directly at a satellite
所以它直接指向卫星
moving across the sky
划过天空
and third
第三
we'll dive into what exactly the dish and satellite
我们将深入研究天线和卫星到底是什么
are sending inside the beam
正在光束内部发送
that results in your ability to stream
这导致你能够流式传输
five HD movies or shows simultaneously
同时HD电影或表演
this video is quite long as it's full of
这个视频很长，因为它充满了
in depth details
深入的细节
we recommend watching it first at
我们建议先在
125 times speed
125倍速度
and then a second time
然后第二次
at one and a half speed
以一个半的速度
to understand it as a complete technology
将其理解为一项完整的技术
so stick around and let's jump right in
所以留下来，让我们跳进去
first let's start by clarifying
首先让我们从澄清开始
the difference between a television satellite dish
电视卫星天线的区别
such as this one
比如这个
and the Starlink ground dish which Elon Musk dubbed
埃隆·马斯克称之为星链研磨盘
dishy mcfatface
盘状麦特法斯
or dishy for short
或者简称盘
TV dishes use a parabolic reflector
电视碟子使用抛物面反射器
to focus the electromagnetic waves
聚焦电磁波
which are the TV signals
哪些是电视信号
sent from broadcast satellites
从广播卫星发出
orbiting the earth at an altitude of
绕地球运行的高度为
35 thousand kilometers
3.50万公里
TV satellite dishes only receive TV signals from space
电视卫星天线只接收来自太空的电视信号
they can't send data
他们无法发送数据
dishy however
然而
both sends and receives internet data
发送和接收互联网数据
from a Starlink satellite
来自星链卫星
orbiting
轨道运行
550 kilometers away
550公里以外
while the Starlink satellite is
而星链卫星
60 times closer than TV satellites
比电视卫星近60倍
it's still an incredible distance
这仍然是难以置信的距离
to wirelessly send a signal
无线发送信号
and thus
因此
the beams between dishy and the Starlink satellite
Dish和星链卫星之间的光束
need to be focused into tight
需要专注于紧密
powerful beams
强力光束
they're continuously angled
它们是连续成角度的
or steered to point at one another
或者转向彼此
compare this to TV broadcast signals
将此与电视广播信号进行比较
which come from a satellite the size of a van
来自一个货车大小的卫星
and whose signals propagate in a wide fan
其信号在宽风扇中传播
that covers land masses larger than North America
覆盖了比北美还大的陆地
table sized starling satellites however
然而桌子大小的八哥卫星
need to be in a low earth orbit orbit to provide for
需要在近地轨道轨道上提供
20 milliseconds latency
20毫秒延迟
which is critical for smoothly playing internet games
这对于流畅地玩网络游戏至关重要
or surfing the web
或上网
and as a result their coverage is much smaller
因此，他们的覆盖面要小得多
thus 10,000 or more starling satellites
因此10,000或更多的八哥卫星
all orbiting at incredibly fast speeds
都以惊人的速度在轨道上运行
in a low earth orbit
在近地轨道上
are required to provide satellite internet
需要提供卫星互联网
to the entire earth
到整个地球
let's now open up dishing mcfatface
现在让我们打开餐盘McFatface
at the back we have a pair of motors
在后面我们有一对马达
and an Ethernet cable that connects to the router
和连接路由器的以太网电缆
note that these motors don't continuously move dishing
请注意，这些电机不会连续移动洗盘
we need to point directly at the Starling satellite
我们需要直接指向Starling卫星
they're used only for initial setup
它们仅用于初始设置
to get the dish pointed in the proper
把盘子指向正确的位置
general direction
大方向
opening up dishy
打开盘子
we find an aluminum structural back plate
我们找到一个铝制结构背板
on the other side
在另一边
we find a massive printed circuit board or PCB
我们发现一块巨大的印刷电路板或PCB
one side has 640
一边有640
small microchips
小型微芯片
and 20 larger microchips
和20个更大的微芯片
organized in a pattern with very intricate traces
以非常复杂的痕迹图案组织
fanning out from the larger to smaller microchips
从大芯片向小芯片扩散
along with additional chips including the main CPU
以及包括主CPU在内的附加芯片
and GPS module
和GPS模块
on the edge of the PCB
在PCB的边缘
on the other side are
另一边是
1400 ish copper circles
1400 ish铜圈
with a grid of squares between the circles
圆圈之间有正方形网格
on the next layer
在下一层
there's a rubber honeycomb pattern with small
有一个橡胶蜂窝图案，有小
notched copper circles
缺口铜圆
and behind that
而在这背后
we find another honeycomb pattern
我们发现另一个蜂窝图案
and then the front side of dishy
然后是盘子的正面
so what are we looking at well in essence we have
那么我们在看什么呢？本质上我们有什么？
1280 antennas arranged in a hexagonal honeycomb pattern
1280根天线排列成六边形蜂窝图案
with
与
each stack of copper circles being a single antenna
每叠铜圈就是一个天线
controlled by the microchips
由微芯片控制
on the PCB this massive array works together
在PCB上，这个巨大的阵列协同工作
in what's called a phased array
在所谓的相控阵中
in order to send and receive electromagnetic waves
为了收发电磁波
that are angled to and from a Starlink satellite
与星链卫星成一定角度
orbiting
轨道运行
550 kilometers above
上面550公里
let's zoom in and see how a single antenna operates
让我们放大看看单个天线是如何工作的
here we have an aperture coupled patch antenna
这里我们有一个孔径耦合贴片天线
composed of six layers
由六层组成
most of which are inside the PCB
大部分都在PCB内部
it looks very different from the antenna
看起来和天线很不一样
of an old school radio
旧学校收音机
and is honestly incredibly complicated
老实说，这非常复杂。
so let's simplify it
所以让我们简化它
we'll remove a few of the layers for now
我们暂时去掉几层
and step through
并跨过
the basic principles of how
如何的基本原则
we generate an electromagnetic wave
我们会产生电磁波
that propagates out from this antenna
从这个天线传播出去
to start at the bottom
从底部开始
we have a micro strip transmission line feed
我们有微带传输线馈源
coming from one of the small microchips
来自其中一个小型微芯片
this transmission line feed is just a copper PCB trace
这个传输线馈送只是一个铜PCB迹线
or wire that abruptly ends under the antenna stack
或者在天线堆下突然结束的电线
we send a 12 gigahertz high frequency voltage
我们发送一个12千兆赫的高频电压
or signal to the feed wire
或信号到馈送线
which is a voltage that goes up and down
这是一个上升和下降的电压
in a sinusoidal fashion
以正弦的方式
going from positive to negative and back to positive
从积极到消极再回到积极
once every 83 picoseconds
每83皮秒一次
12 billion times a second or 12 gigahertz
每秒120亿次或者12千兆赫
note that high frequency electricity
注意高频电
works differently from direct current
工作原理与直流电不同
or low frequency
或低频
50 or 60 hertz household electricity
50或60赫兹家用电力
for example above the copper feed wire
例如铜馈线上方
we have a copper circle with notches cut into it
我们有一个铜圆圈，上面有缺口。
called an antenna patch
叫做天线贴片
with DC or low frequency alternating current
直流或低频交流电
there wouldn't be much happening
就不会有什么事发生了
because the patch is isolated
因为补丁是孤立的
but with a high frequency signal
但有高频信号
the power sent to the feed wire is coupled
发送到馈电线的电源被耦合
or sent to the patch
或发送到补丁
how exactly does this happen
这到底是怎么发生的？
well as mentioned earlier
正如前面提到的
a 12 gigahertz signal is applied
应用12 GHz信号
to the copper feed wire
到铜馈电线
when the voltage is at the bottom of its sinusoidal
当电压在其正弦曲线的底部时
or trough we have a concentration of electrons
或者通过我们有一个电子浓度
pushed to the end of the feed wire
推到馈送线的末端
thus creating a zone of negative charge
从而产生一个负电荷区
which corresponds to the maximum negative voltage
这对应于最大负电压
this concentration of electrons on the tip of the wire
电线尖端的电子集中
repels all electrons away
排斥所有的电子
including the electrons on the top of the patch
包括贴片顶部的电子
and as a result
结果是
these electrons are pushed to the other side of
这些电子被推到的另一边
the circular patch
圆形补丁
thus one side of the patch becomes positively charged
因此贴片的一侧带有正电荷
while the other becomes negatively charged
而另一个则带负电荷
thereby creating electric fields
从而产生电场
between the patch and feed wire
在贴片和馈线之间
like so however
像这样然而
when we reverse the voltage to the copper feed wire 42
当我们将电压反转到铜馈线42时
picoseconds later
皮秒后
we have a concentration of positive charges
我们有正电荷的集中
or a lack of electrons at the end of the wire
或者电线末端缺少电子
and thus the electrons in the patch
因此贴片中的电子
flow to the other side
流向另一边
the voltage in the patch is flipped
贴片中的电压翻转
and the direction of the electric fields are also
电场的方向也是
flipped
翻转
because the feed wire voltage oscillates back and forth
因为馈线电压来回振荡
42 picoseconds between one peak and trough
一个波峰和波谷之间有42皮秒
the electric fields in the patch will also oscillate
贴片中的电场也会振荡
as the electrons
作为电子
or current flows back and forth
或电流来回流动
if we pause the oscillation
如果我们暂停振荡
we can see some of these electric field vectors
我们可以看到一些电场矢量
or arrows from the patch
或补丁上的箭头
are vertical
垂直
and because they're equal and opposite they cancel out
因为它们是平等和相反的，所以它们抵消了
however other electric fields are horizontal
然而其他电场是水平的
in the same plane of the patch
在补丁的同一平面上
and are called fringing fields
被称为边缘地带
these fringing fields are in the same direction
这些边缘区域在同一个方向
and thus they add to each other
因此它们相互添加
resulting in a combined electric field
形成一个复合电场
pointing in this direction
指向这个方向
at the same time
同时
electrons
电子
flowing from one side of the disk to the other
从圆盘的一边流到另一边
which is an electric current
也就是电流
generate a magnetic field with a strength
产生具有强度的磁场
and direction
和方向
or vector
或向量
perpendicular to the fringing electric field vector
垂直于边缘电场矢量
as a result we have an electric field pointing one way
结果我们有一个电场指向一个方向
and a magnetic field pointing perpendicular to that
磁场垂直于此
let's move forward in time
让我们在时间中前进
to where the voltage on the feed line becomes positive
到馈电线路上的电压变为正值的地方
and now we're at the peak of the sinusoid
现在我们在正弦曲线的顶峰
42 picoseconds later
42皮秒后
the charge concentrations or voltage
电荷浓度或电压
as well as the current is all flipped
以及电流都翻转了
and thus the electric
因此电动
and magnetic fields point in the opposite directions
磁场指向相反的方向
electric and magnetic fields
电场和磁场
propagate in all directions
四通八达
and by creating these oscillating fields
通过创造这些振荡场
we've generated an electromagnetic wave
我们产生了电磁波
which travels in the direction
它沿着这个方向行进
perpendicular to both the electric
垂直于两个电动
and magnetic field vectors
和磁场矢量
because the two sets of field vectors are not
因为两组场向量不是
all in the same plane
都在同一个平面上
but rather are curved
而是弯曲的
the propagating electromagnetic wave
传播的电磁波
travels outwards
向外传播
in an expanding shell or balloon like fashion
以膨胀的外壳或气球状的方式
kind of like a light bulb on the ceiling
有点像天花板上的灯泡
let's simplify the visuals
让我们简化视觉效果
so we can see the peak and trough
所以我们可以看到波峰和波谷
or top and bottom of each wave
或每个波浪的顶部和底部
and note that the trough is just a vector
并注意槽只是一个向量
pointed in the opposite direction
指向相反的方向
additionally the strengths of these
此外，这些的优势
field vectors directly relate back to the voltage
场矢量直接与电压相关
and signal
和信号
that we originally sent to the copper microstrip
我们最初发送到铜微带
feed wire at the bottom of the stack
堆栈底部的馈线
which means
这意味着
if we want to make these electric and magnetic fields
如果我们想制造这些电场和磁场
stronger we just have to increase the voltage
更强，我们只需要增加电压
sent to the feed line
发送到馈送线
it's like a dimmer on a light switch
就像电灯开关上的调光器
more power equals a brighter light
更多的力量等于更亮的光
thus far we've been talking about this
到目前为止，我们一直在谈论这个
aperture coupled patch antenna as transmitting
孔径耦合贴片天线作为发射
however it can also be used for receiving a signal
但是它也可以用于接收信号
in this microchip called a front end module
在这个叫做前端模块的微芯片中
we switch the antenna from transmit to receive
我们把天线从发射切换到接收
and turn off the 12 gigahertz signal
并关闭12 GHz信号
when an electromagnetic wave
当电磁波
from the satellite is directed towards dishy
从卫星上指向了盘子
the electric fields from this incoming
来自这个输入的电场
the signal
信号
will influence the electrons in the copper patch
会影响铜贴片中的电子
thus generating an oscillating flow of electrons
从而产生振荡的电子流
this received high frequency signal
这收到了高频信号
is then coupled to the feed line
然后耦合到馈送线
where it's sent to the front end module chip
它被发送到前端模块芯片的地方
which amplifies the signal
放大信号
thus these antennas can be used to both transmit
因此，这些天线可以用来发射
and receive electromagnetic waves
并接收电磁波
but not at the same time
但不是同时
two quick things to first
先做两件事
as seen earlier
如前所述
this antenna has many more layers
这个天线有很多层
and is more complicated than we've discussed
比我们讨论的要复杂得多
for example here are two circular patches
例如，这里有两个圆形补丁
the bottom is used to transmit at 13 gigahertz
底部用于以13 GHz传输
while the top to receive at
而顶部要在
117 gigahertz
117千兆赫
additionally there are two H slots
另外还有两个H槽
and two feed wires to support circular polarization
和两根馈电线以支持圆极化
a reflective plane in the back
后面的反光平面
and also there are multiple features
而且还有多种功能
for isolating the operation of one antenna
用于隔离一根天线的操作
from the adjacent antennas
从相邻的天线
we've included these
我们已经包含了这些
and many more details in the creator's comments
以及创作者评论中的更多细节
which you can find in the English Canadian subtitles
你可以在英语加拿大字幕中找到
the second note
第二个音符
is that there are electromagnetic waves
就是有电磁波
of all different frequencies
所有不同的频率
from thousands of different sources
来自数千个不同的来源
passing through every point on earth
穿过地球上的每一个点
whether it be visible light from the sun
无论是来自太阳的可见光
radio waves from radio or cell towers
来自无线电或手机信号塔的无线电波
or TV signals from satellites or towers
或来自卫星或塔的电视信号
therefore in order to block out
因此为了阻止
all other frequencies of electromagnetic waves
电磁波的所有其他频率
these antenna patches are designed with very
这些天线贴片的设计非常
exact dimensions
精确尺寸
so that they receive and transmit
以便他们接收和传输
only a very narrow range of frequencies
只有非常狭窄的频率范围
and all the other frequencies outside this range
以及这个范围之外的所有其他频率
are essentially ignored by the antenna
基本上被天线忽略了
let's move on
让我们继续前进
and see how
看看如何
a single antenna can be combined with others
单个天线可以与其他天线组合
in order to amplify the beam to reach outer space
为了放大光束到达外太空
this single antenna
这个单天线
is only a centimeter or so in diameter
直径只有一厘米左右
and using only it would be like turning on
只使用它就像打开一样
and off one light bulb
关掉一个灯泡
and trying to see it
并试图看到它
from the International Space Station
从国际空间站
what we need is a way to make the light
我们需要的是一种方法来制造光
a few thousand times brighter
亮几千倍
and then focus
然后集中注意力
all the electromagnetic waves into a single
所有的电磁波变成一个单一的
powerful beam
强力光束
enter the massive Mr Mcfat face PCB
进入巨大的McFat先生脸PCB
55 centimeters wide with a total of
55厘米宽，总共有
1280 identical antennas in a hexagonal array
六角形阵列中的1280个相同天线
the technique of combining all the antennas
结合所有天线的技术
power together
合力
is called beam forming
被称为光束形成
so how does it work
那么它是如何工作的呢？
well let's first see what happens
好吧，让我们先看看会发生什么
when we have two simplified antennas
当我们有两个简化的天线时
spaced a short distance away
间隔很短的距离
as mentioned before
如前所述
one antenna generates an electromagnetic wave
一根天线产生电磁波
that propagates outwards in a balloon shape
以气球形状向外传播
at every single point in space
在空间的每一个点
there's only one electric field vector
只有一个电场矢量
with a strength and direction
有力量和方向
and thus the two antennas
因此两个天线
oscillating electric field vectors combine together
振荡电场矢量结合在一起
at all points in space
在空间的所有点
in some areas
在某些地区
the electric fields from the antennas
天线产生的电场
are pointing in the same direction
都指向同一个方向
with overlapping peaks
有重叠的峰
and thus add together via constructive interference
从而通过相长干涉相加
and in other locations
在其他地方
they're opposite with one peak on one trough
它们的对立面是一个波峰和一个波谷
and thus
因此
they cancel each other via destructive interference
它们通过相消干涉相互抵消
we can now see that the zone where they add together
我们现在可以看到它们相加的区域
constructively
建设性地
is far tighter
要紧得多
or more focused than a single antenna alone
或者比单个天线更聚焦
when we add even more antennas
当我们添加更多天线时
the zone of constructive interference
相长干涉区
becomes even more focused
变得更加专注
in what is called a beam front
在所谓的梁前
thus by adding
因此通过添加
1280 antennas together
1280根天线在一起
we can form a beam
我们可以形成一道光束
with so much intensity and directionality
有这么多的强度和方向
that it can reach outer space
它可以到达外太空
now
现在
you might be thinking that the strength of one antenna
你可能会想一根天线的强度
duplicates traveled
重复旅行
1280 times over would result in a combined power of
超过1280倍会导致
well 1280 times a single antenna
井1280乘以单天线
but you'd be mistaken
但你肯定搞错了
the effective power and range of the main beam
主梁的有效功率和范围
from all these antennas combined
从所有这些天线的组合
is actually closer to 3500 times that
实际上接近3500倍
of a single antenna
单天线
the quick explanation
快速解释
is that by having these patterns of constructive
通过这些建设性的模式
and destructive interference
和破坏性干扰
it's as if we took a single antenna
就像我们拿了一根天线
multiplied it by 1280
乘以1280
and then placed a whole bunch of mirrors around it
然后在它周围放了一大堆镜子
and left only a single hole for the main beam to exit
只留下一个洞让主梁离开
through
通过
the long explanation requires a ton of math and physics
冗长的解释需要大量的数学和物理知识
so let's move on
所以让我们继续前进
dishy Mcflatface and the Starling satellites
迪西·麦克弗拉法斯和八哥卫星
undoubtedly
毋庸置疑
have some rather complicated science and engineering
有一些相当复杂的科学和工程
inside and to fully comprehend it all
并完全理解这一切
you have to be a multi disciplinary student
你必须是一个多学科的学生
to help you do that
帮你做到这一点
check out brilliant which is sponsoring this video
看看赞助这个视频的辉煌
brilliant is an amazing tool for learning
辉煌是一个惊人的学习工具
they teach a wide range of stem topics in hands on
他们在实践中教授广泛的词干主题
interactive ways
互动方式
many of which directly relate to Starlink
其中许多与星链直接相关
and other cutting edge technologies
和其他尖端技术
such as electric cars
比如电动汽车
quantum computers
量子计算机
rocketry
火箭学
or neural networks
或者神经网络
for example
例如
they have an entire course dedicated to waves
他们有专门针对海浪的课程
and light and another one on gravitational physics
还有一个是关于引力物理学的
which will greatly help in understanding Starlink
这将大大有助于理解星链
and Spacex rockets
和SpaceX火箭
brilliant is nothing like a boring textbook but rather
辉煌一点也不像无聊的教科书，而是
all the courses use interactive modules
所有课程都使用交互式模块
to make the lessons entertaining
让课程变得有趣
and to help the concepts stick in your head
并帮助这些概念在你脑海中扎根
to really understand today's frontier technologies
要真正了解当今的前沿技术
and to help you become a revolutionary engineer and
帮助你成为一名革命性的工程师
entrepreneur like Elon Musk
像埃隆·马斯克这样的企业家
you have to be versed in a wide range of fields
你必须精通广泛的领域
in science and engineering
在科学和工程中
we recommend you sign up
我们建议您注册
try out some of the lessons for free and
免费试用一些课程
if you like them
如果你喜欢他们
which we're sure you will
我们相信你会的
sign up for an annual subscription
注册年度订阅
to the viewers of this channel
致该频道的观众
brilliant is offering
辉煌是提供
20 percent off an annual subscription to the first 200
前200名的年度订阅可享受20%的折扣
people who sign up
报名的人
just go to brilliant
去辉煌吧
org
组织
brancheducation
分支教育
you can find that link in the description below
您可以在下面的描述中找到该链接
now let's continue exploring
现在让我们继续探索
how a powerful beam can be continuously
强大的光束如何连续
swept across the sky
掠过天空
and then
然后
how we fill it with hundreds of megabits of data
我们如何用数百兆比特的数据填充它
every second as a quick refresher from before
每一秒都像以前一样快速复习
here's an array of 1280 antennas
这是由1280个天线组成的阵列
and we fed them all with the same
我们用同样的食物喂他们
12 gigahertz signal
12千兆赫信号
in order to create a laser like beam
为了制造出类似激光的光束
propagating perpendicular to dishy
垂直于盘状繁殖的
however as mentioned earlier
然而如前所述
we need to be able to angle this beam
我们要能让光束倾斜
so that it points
所以它指向
directly at the Starlink satellite
直接对着星链卫星
zooming across the sky at
划过天空
27 thousand kilometers per hour
每小时2.70万公里
using the motors isn't feasible
使用马达是不可行的
because they would break within a month
因为它们会在一个月内破裂
and aren't accurate enough
而且不够准确
so the solution is to use what's called
所以解决方案是使用所谓的
phased array beam steering
相控阵波束转向
let's go back to our two antenna example
让我们回到我们的两个天线示例
before
以前
we were feeding the same signal to the two antennas
我们向两个天线发送相同的信号
and thus the antennas were in phase with one another
因此这些天线彼此成相位
understanding phase is critical
理解阶段至关重要
so quickly
这么快
changing the height or amplitude of the signal
改变信号的高度或幅度
is done by changing the powers sent to the antenna
是通过改变发送到天线的功率来完成的
thus making the signal stronger or weaker
从而使信号更强或更弱
the frequency is how many peaks and troughs
频率是多少波峰和波谷
or wavelengths there are in one second
或者一秒钟内的波长
and changing the phase
并改变相位
is shifting the signal left or right
正在向左或向右移动信号
phase shifting is measured in degrees between 0 and 359
相移是在0到359度之间测量的
because if we shift the signal 360 degrees
因为如果我们360度转换信号
or one full wavelength
或者一个全波长
then we're back at the beginning
那我们又回到了起点
exactly as if we were to loop around a circle
就像我们绕着一个圆圈转一样
for example
例如
here's a signal with a 45 degree phase shift
这是一个相移45度的信号
here's another with a 180 degree shift
这是另一个180度的位移
and then another with a 315 degree shift
然后是另一个315度的位移
your eyes can't see differences in phase shifted
你的眼睛看不到相位变化的差异
visible light
可见光
however
然而
high tech circuitry such as what's inside dishy
高科技电路，比如盘子里的东西
is really good at detecting
真的很擅长探测
and working with phase shifts
并使用相移
so then how do we use phase shifting
那么我们如何使用相移呢？
to angle the beam
使光束倾斜
and have it point directly at the satellite
让它直接指向卫星
the solution is to phase shift
解决方案是相移
the signal sent to one antenna
发送到一根天线的信号
with respect to the other antenna
相对于另一个天线
and as a result
结果是
the timing of the peaks and troughs
波峰和波谷的时间
emitted from one antenna
从一根天线发射
is different from the other
与其他不同
these peaks and troughs propagate outwards
这些波峰和波谷向外传播
and the location of the constructive interference
以及相长干涉的位置
is now angled to the left
现在向左倾斜
with destructive interference everywhere else
到处都有破坏性的干扰
if we change the phase of the antennas again
如果我们再次改变天线的相位
the zone of constructive interference is angled to the
相长干涉区与
right therefore
对因此
by continuously changing the phase of the signals
通过不断改变信号的相位
sent to the antennas
发送到天线
we can create a sweeping
我们可以创建一个清扫
zone of constructive interference
相长干扰区
let's bring in six more antennas
再装六个天线
and simplify the visual
并简化视觉
so that we only see a section of the peaks from each
所以我们只能看到每个山峰的一部分
wave far away from the antennas
远离天线挥手
the waves join to form a wavefront
波浪结合形成波阵面
that is a planar wave
那是平面波
kind of like ocean waves crashing on a shoreline
有点像海浪冲击海岸线
just as before
就像以前一样
by continuously changing
通过不断变化
using the timing
利用时机
of when each wave peak is emitted by each antenna
每个天线何时发射每个波峰
we can change the angle
我们可以换个角度
at which the wavefront is formed
波阵面形成的位置
essentially
本质上
steering the beam in one direction or another
将光束转向一个方向或另一个方向
and if we bring in more antennas
如果我们有更多的天线
in a two dimensional array
在二维数组中
we can now steer the beam in any direction
我们现在可以把光束转向任何方向
within a 100 degree field of view
在100度的视野范围内
let's move back to view all 1280 antennas in dishy
让我们回过头来看一下所有1280根天线
in order to know the exact angle
为了知道确切的角度
the beam needs to be pointed
光束需要指向
or steered we use the GPS coordinates of dishy
或者转向我们使用盘的GPS坐标
from this chip over here
从这里的芯片
along with the orbital position of the Starling
还有八哥的轨道位置
satellite which is known in dishy software
在磁盘软件中已知的卫星
the software computes the exact set of 3d angles
该软件计算精确的3d角度集
and the required phase shift for each of the antennas
以及每个天线所需的相移
these phase shift results are then sent to the 20
然后将这些相移结果发送到20
larger chips called beamformers
称为波束形成器的更大芯片
and each beamformer coordinates between
和每个波束形成器之间的坐标
32 smaller chips called front end modules
32个称为前端模块的较小芯片
each of which controls two antennas
每个控制两个天线
every few microseconds
每隔几微秒
these computations are recalculated
这些计算被重新计算
and disseminated
并传播
to all the microchips
到所有的微芯片
in order to perfectly aim the beam at the satellite
为了完美地将光束对准卫星
as a result the beam can be steered
因此，光束可以被操纵
anywhere in 100 degree field of view
100度视野中的任何地方
there are a few quick notes
有几个快速笔记
first the main beam also called the main lobe
首先，主梁也称为主瓣
looks like this
看起来像这样
however constructive and destructive
无论多么有建设性和破坏性
interference isn't perfect
干扰并不完美
and as a result
结果是
there are additional side lobes of lesser power
另外还有功率较小的旁瓣
third Mr Mcfat face holds a single phased array
第三张McFat先生的脸拿着一个相控阵
however on the Starlink satellite
然而在星链卫星上
there are in fact four phased array antennas
实际上有四个相控阵天线
two are used to communicate with multiple dishes
两个用于与多个盘子通信
and two
二
are used to communicate with the ground stations
是用来和地面站联系的
to relay the internet traffic
转发互联网流量
and fourth phased arrays are used in many applications
和第四相控阵用于许多应用
and interestingly
有趣的是
they're used on commercial airlines
它们用于商业航空公司
to allow for mid flight internet
允许飞行中上网
so this video
所以这个视频
also tangentially explains
也间接解释了
how midflight internet works
飞行中互联网是如何工作的
before we explore how actual data is sent
在我们探索如何发送实际数据之前
we want to mention that
我们想提一下
this video took a month to research
这个视频花了一个月的时间研究
two dozen script revisions
两打剧本修改
and two months to model and animate
还有两个月的时间来建模和制作动画
if your mind is blown
如果你头脑发热
by the complexity of this technology
这项技术的复杂性
and the depth of this video
以及这段视频的深度
click the subscribe button
点击订阅按钮
like this video
喜欢这个视频
write a comment below
在下面写评论
and we'll be sure to create more videos like this one
我们一定会制作更多像这样的视频
the third topic we're going to dive into
我们将深入讨论的第三个主题
is how information gets sent between Dishi
是如何在Dishi之间发送信息的
and the Starlink satellite
还有星链卫星
for example we've talked about high frequency
例如，我们已经讨论过高频
sinusoid shaped electromagnetic waves
正弦形电磁波
but that doesn't look anything like binary
但这看起来一点也不像二进制。
and even less like your favorite TV show
更不像你最喜欢的电视节目
so what's happening
那么发生了什么？
well dishy and the satellite
井盘和卫星
indeed send a signal that looks like this
确实发出了看起来像这样的信号
however they vary the amplitude
然而，它们会改变幅度
and the phase of the transmitted signal
和发射信号的相位
and then assign or encode
然后分配或编码
6 bit binary
6位二进制
values to each different combination or permutation
每个不同组合或排列的值
of amplitude and phase
振幅和相位
with 6 bits there are 64 different values
6位有64个不同的值
and thus we need
因此我们需要
64 different permutations of amplitude and phase
64种不同的振幅和相位排列
however instead of listing all the permutations
然而，与其列出所有排列
it's more
更多
easily visualized by arranging the 64 different values
通过排列64个不同的值轻松可视化
in a graph called a constellation
在一个叫做星座的图表中
diagram is shown
显示图表
let's look at the point 0 1 1 0 1
让我们看看点0 1 1 0 1
and draw a line from the origin to this point
并从原点到这一点画一条线
the distance from the origin is
距原点的距离是
the amplitude of the signal
信号的幅度
and the angle from the positive x axis is the phase
与正x轴的角度是相位
it's a bit like using polar coordinates
有点像用极坐标
thus for dishy to send these 6 bits
因此，对于碟子来说，发送这6位。
it transmits a signal with an amplitude of 59 percent
它传输的信号幅度为59%
and a phase shift of 121 degrees
和121度的相移
then if the next value being sent is 101000
那么如果发送的下一个值是101000
the signal switches to
信号切换到
an 87 percent amplitude of brightness
87%的亮度幅度
and a 305 degree phase shift
和305度的相移
after that it sends the next value
之后它发送下一个值
with a different amplitude and phase shift
具有不同的幅度和相移
each of these 6 bit groupings are called symbols
这6位分组中的每一个都称为符号
and they last for only 10 or so nanoseconds
它们只持续10纳秒左右
before the next symbol is sent
在发送下一个符号之前
lots of times you see the signal scrunched up like this
很多时候你会看到信号像这样折叠起来
however
然而
because the frequency of the signal is just once every
因为信号的频率只是每隔一次
83 picoseconds or
83皮秒或
12 gigahertz and since a symbol lasts 10 nanoseconds
12千兆赫由于一个符号持续10纳秒
it's more accurate to have around 120 wavelengths
大约120个波长更准确
per symbol before the next symbol is sent
发送下一个符号之前的每个符号
because we're dealing on the order of picol
因为我们在处理皮科尔的订单。
and nanoseconds
和纳秒
that means that we can fit 90 million 6 bit groups
这意味着我们可以9000万6位组
or symbols resulting in 540
或符号导致540
million bits per second
每秒百万比特
however note
然而注意
that this data transfer is shared between download
此数据搬迁在下载之间共享
and upload since this particular antenna
并从这个特定的天线上传
it can't transmit and receive data at the same time
它不能同时发送和接收数据
about 74 milliseconds of every second
大约每秒74毫秒
is used to send data from dishes
用于从盘子发送数据
to the Starlink satellite
星链卫星
and 926
和926
milliseconds is used to send data from the satellite
毫秒用于从卫星发送数据
down to dishy
非常糟糕
and for the sake of reducing latency
为了减少延迟
these time slots
这些时隙
get distributed throughout a single second
在一秒钟内分发
instead of grouping them all together
而不是把它们组合在一起
this technique of sending
这种发送技术
6 bit values
6位值
using different variations of amplitude and phase
使用不同的振幅和相位变化
is called 64 quam
被称为64 quam
or quadrature amplitude modulation
或正交调幅
and is more complicated than we discussed
比我们讨论的要复杂得多
but let's not get sidetracked
但我们不要转移话题
now that we have a stream of millions of 6 bit symbols
现在我们有数百万个6位符号流
yielding hundreds of megabytes of data per second
每秒产生数百兆字节的数据
in order to turn it into your favorite TV show
为了把它变成你最喜欢的电视节目
we use the Advanced Video Codec
我们使用高级视频编解码器
or H 264 format
或H 264格式
you can learn more about that in our video
您可以在我们的视频中了解更多信息
that explores
探索
image compression shown here
此处显示的图像压缩
I'm sure you have many questions
我肯定你有很多问题
and by all means put them in the comments below
并通过一切方式将它们放在下面的评论中
but before we finish let's clarify two things
但在我们结束之前，让我们澄清两件事
first the scale of practically
首先是实际规模
everything in this video is off
这个视频中的所有内容都关闭了
here's the correct scale of dishy
这是正确的盘子比例
and the Starling satellite
和Starling卫星
however dishy is
无论多么诱人
550 km away which we can't correctly show
550公里外，我们无法正确显示
in stark contrast
形成鲜明对比
the emitted electromagnetic waves are only around
发射的电磁波只在周围
25 centimeters apart
相隔25厘米
and thus between dishy and the satellite
因此在Dish和卫星之间
there are around
周围有
22 million wavelengths
2200万波长
which
哪个
is many more than the few waves that you see here
比你在这里看到的几个波浪要多得多
additionally in this animation
另外在这个动画中
we're showing the wavelengths
我们正在显示波长
slowly making their way up and down
慢慢地上上下下
when actually it only takes around
实际上只需要大约
2 milliseconds
2毫秒
for an electromagnetic wave emitted from dishy
从盘子里发出的电磁波
or the Starlink satellite
或者星链卫星
to reach the other
到达另一个
the second clarification
第二次澄清
is that we disproportionately show dishy
我们不成比例地表现出性感
emitting electromagnetic waves
发射电磁波
and sending them to the satellite
并将它们发送到卫星
in reality
在现实中
the satellite dish is more frequently in receive mode
卫星天线更频繁地处于接收模式
and the steps
和步骤
and physics of receiving an electromagnetic wave
和接收电磁波的物理学
are similar to emitting one
类似于发射一个
just in reverse
正好相反
that's pretty much it
差不多就是这样。
for how Starlink and dishy send data to each other
星链和碟形如何互相发送数据
the original script for this video was over
这个视频的原始脚本已经结束了
45 minutes long
45分钟长
so all the details that were cut
所以所有被切割的细节
got their own in the creator's comments
在创作者的评论中得到了他们自己的
found in the English
在英语中发现
Canada subtitles
加拿大字幕
thank you to all of our Patreon and YouTube membership
感谢我们所有的Patreon和YouTube会员
sponsors for helping to make this video
赞助商帮助制作这个视频
also thank you to Colono Flynn at New AE
也感谢新AE的科洛诺·弗林
Technology for lending us a starling
借给我们八哥的技术
dishy PCB for imaging and research
用于成像和研究的碟形PCB
this is branch education and we create
这是分支教育，我们创造
3d animations that dive deep
深入的3d动画
to the technology that drives our modern world
驱动我们现代世界的技术
watch another branch video
观看另一个分支视频
by clicking one of these cards
通过点击其中一张卡片
or click here to subscribe
或点击这里订阅
thanks for watching to the end
感谢收看到最后